

Gustavo Frosi

Doutorando em Ciência do Solo - UFRGS

- Porto Alegre, RS
- Brasileiro

Habilidade

R	4 anos.
Rmarkdown	2 anos.
Quarto	1 ano.
Análise de dados	5 anos.
Visualização de dados	2 anos.

Ferramentas

- RStudio
- Pacote Office

Contato

- Porto Alegre, RS
- *→* +55 49 98885-4446
- gustavofrosi@hotmail.com
- gustavofrosi.com.br
- FGu5tav0

Resumo

Sou Gustavo Frosi, engenheiro agrônomo e mestre em Ciência do Solo, com uma trajetória acadêmica marcada pela busca constante por conhecimento. Natural de Ouro Verde - Santa Catarina, atualmente resido em Porto Alegre - Rio Grande do Sul. Desde a iniciação científica, dediquei-me ao estudo do solo, participando de variados experimentos de campo e laboratório. No mestrado, concentrei-me nas propriedades químicas e físicas do solo e o impacto do uso de resíduos. Atualmente, no doutorado, meu foco é o potássio e como otimizar sua recomendação para uso mais eficiente. Minha experiência com análise de dados começou cedo e se desenvolveu em uma paixão, resultando em amplo conhecimento em manipulação e visualização de dados, especialmente com o R.

Experiência

Team Lead for Transparent Social Analytics

03/2022 - Present

Department of Computational Social Science GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences

I am coordinating a project to build an Open Science platform with reusable code and tutorials to analyze digital behaviour data. I am also doing research on Open Science practices and I implement tools to enhance reproducibility and make methods accessible in ${\sf R}$

Presidential Fellow

09/2018 - 02/2022

Sociology Department University of Manchester

I did research on Disinformation on Social Media which involved the analysis of large scale and unstructured data sets with R and Bash

Post Doctoral Researcher

11/2017 - 08/2018

Chair of Social Networks ETH Zurich

I developed new methods to analyze social networks and I gathered and analyzed large datsets from Social Media APIs

Post Doctoral Researcher

10/2015 - 10/2017

Department of Computer & Information Science University of Konstanz

I developed new methods to analyze social networks and scraped, harmonized, and analyzed a large corpus of football data

Ph.D. Candidate

11/2012 - 09/2015

Department of Computer & Information Science University of Konstanz

I developed new methods to analyze social networks and implemented these methods in R packages using R and C++

Educação

Engenheiro agrônomo

02/2015 - 12/2019

Instituto Federal do Paraná (IFPR)

TCC: Sorção e fracionamento de fósforo em solos subtropicais de diferentes mineralogias

Mestrado em Ciência do Solo

03/2020 - 03/2022

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS)

Dissertação: Dinâmica química, física e mineralógica de um Latossolo com aplicação de resíduo industrial orgânico-salino

Doutorado em Ciência do Solo

03/2022 - Presente

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS)

Tese: Adubação potássica em solos tropicais e subtropicais e uso de parâmetros químicos-mineralógicos para estimar a disponibilidade de K

Projetos

See my github profile for a comprehensive list of open source projects.

R packages

Creator and Maintainer

edgebundle, graphlayouts, levelnet, netrankr, netUtils, networkdata, PSAWR, roughnet, roughsf, rtoot, Rtumblr, signnet, snahelper, webbotparseR, webtrackR

R packages

Contributor

backbone, ggraph, multigraphr, netropy, rang, rgraph6

Quarto extensions

Creator and Maintainer

Academicons (shortcodes), Blackboard (revealjs theme), sketchy (html theme), share buttons (filter), nutshell (filter), quartocities (website template), quartocv (cv templates)

soccerverse.com (football analytics website)

Creator and Maintainer

Manual and automated gathering of football results around the world, Harmonizing data (e.g. club names and managers), Implementation of ranking algorithms, Predicting of league tables and matchforecasting, Uses R, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, around 1000 visitors/month